Guide to the Basil Davenport Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Basil Davenport papers
1899-1964
YCAL MSS 489
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9.08
(26 boxes)
The Basil Davenport Papers consist chiefly of correspondence, including a substantial number of outgoing letters from Davenport to his family. The collection also contains Davenport's diaries, drafts of his writings and translations, printed material documenting his career and critical work, and personal papers including genealogical material.
Davenport, Basil, 1905-1966
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of Basil Davenport, July 1966.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Basil Davenport (1905-1966)
Reared in Louisville, Kentucky, Basil Davenport was the eldest of two sons born to Ira William and Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport. A slim and personable aesthete, he never married. At the Taft School he suffered from homesickness, but won distinction as an editor of the school's literary magazine, debater and thespian. At Yale he continued these pursuits and took up boxing before graduating in 1926. Then he studied classics for two years at Oxford and taught Greek tor a year at Rutgers after returning to this country.
From childhood Davenport cultivated a facility for storytelling, especially the genre of tale associated with campfires. This proclivity delighted both his peers and his elders, and subsequently it led to his numerous anthologies, especially: Ghostly tales to be told; a collection of stories from the great masters, arranged for reading and telling aloud (1950) and Tales to be told in the dark; a selection of stories from the great authors, arranged for reading and telling aloud (1953). Other notable anthologies were: The Portable Roman Reader (1951) and The Selected Works of Stephen Vincent Benét (1942). His translations of Rostand's L'Aiglon (issued by the Yale Press in 1927) and Aeschylus The Oresteia were performed at Yale during his Freshman and Senior years respectively. Two original works were: An Inquiry Into Science Fiction (1955) and An Introduction to Islandia (1942).
After his year at Rutgers he settled in New York, contributing book reviews and feature articles to The Saturday Review of Literature and performing similar services for the Book-of-the-Month Club News. From 1936 until his death, he was associated with the latter organization, first as Editorial Assistant and from 1956-1966 as one of the five judges, at whose monthly meetings the final selections were voted.
His virtually inexhaustible store of classical and literary lore served him well on various quiz programs, notably "Down You Go." Unfortunately it was scratched soon after he joined it, due to scandals precipitated when other programs were exposed as "fixed."
Scope and Contents
The papers of Basil Davenport (1905-1966) comprise 26 boxes and 12,000 pages of material. Davenport's outgoing letters to members of the family, especially his mother, number 7501 pages and fill the first 13 boxes. A few of these are holographs written in childhood or while he was absent from home. Others are signed typescripts. But the majority are carbons retained by him for his own file. Early in his letters he formed the habit of dating them by the name of the day instead of in the usual way. Designations such as Christmas and Twelfth Night are easily understood but the identification of Lady's Day, Saint Distaff's Day and many of the lesser known Saint's Days requires the use of an Almanac.
The collection contains 273 pages of original manuscript. There are also three loose-leaf notebooks known as "His Book", with 464 pages of early prose, verse and letters. None of these are originals, however, as they were copied (mostly in typescript) and assembled by Davenport's "Aunt Dudy," Mrs. Juliet (Pritte) Belknap, who died in 1948. The whole collection reached Yale as a result of Davenport's own bequest.
The day-to-day details of Davenport's life as reflected in the long letters to his mother are supplemented by diaries begun in 1925 and sustained from 1935 to 1964, with numerous gaps while be traveled abroad, vacationed at Pemaquid Point, Maine, or served in the second world war. The diaries provide a more humdrum record than the letters, with emphasis on such trivialities as the pleasures and pains of mint juleps and Grade A or Grade B hangovers. That Davenport himself was more satisfied with the letters than with the diaries is shown by the entry for July 28, 1960, written while his mother's health was rapidly deteriorating: "All my life I have been half-satisfying my creative urge by my letters, especially to her. Can it find another outlet [when she is gone]?"
Before Davenport reached thirteen, Edwin Markham praised his poetic efforts in an August 26, 1918 letter to Emily Davenport acknowledging receipt of an "Illuminated missal" prepared in his honor by "young poet Basil... It seems to me that Basil's poems show unusual promise [with] here and there...a freshness of phrase that is very gratifying...Tell him to send me more of his verses in the coming months." (A copy of this missal remains among Davenport's manuscripts and is also included in "His Book".) A second enthusiastic letter from Markham dated five years later is in Series II.
Other correspondents represented in the collection are six members of the Benét family, Bennett Cerf, Francis Welch Crowinshield, Clifton Fadiman, Amy Loveman, Fletcher Pratt and Edgar Montillon Woolley. That Davenport's contemporaries appreciated his erudition is shown by this couplet from a twenty-eight line effusion by Raymond Holden subtitled: "Not Any Davenport Will Do in a Storm," composed on the eve of the subject's departure for the second world war:
We need men, but the Army is needier,
So here is Basil, our Encyclopedia,...
The letters Davenport wrote to his mother in August, 1945 as the second world war was ending, are noteworthy, providing details of his month-long odyssey, as he returned from France by way of Africa and Brazil.
Outstanding among the individual manuscripts preserved in Series V are: "Lancelot at the Chapel of the Grail" (also contained in "His Book"), which was sent to his father from Europe on April 4, 1927; "Legends of Our Lady from Old France" (the "illuminated missal" sent to Edwin Markham in 1918) and affectionate verses "To Mommon," Davenport's grandmother Emily (Andrews) Davison who died in 1925.
These excerpts from his 1955 diary show his continuing concern for the carving of his niche in the literary world:
Jan 25 - Finished the [Book-of-the-Month News] column just before lunch...Not so good as last month's but acceptable to me, and to Harry [Scherman]. Ought to feel very happy, but I don't.
Jan 27 - Almost hate to admit it, but I'm getting reconciled to Hudson Street. I thoroughly enjoy my walk to work in the morning;...and while lunch is not terribly good, it is relaxing to come in and settle down for the day.
Rosemary [Benét]...said "everybody" was talking about my column, and that Amy [Loveman] had spoken to Norman Cousins about getting me to do something regular [for the Saturday Review]. I ought to try to decide what I do want.
Apr 26 - ...but it isn't funny without the drinks - and without my intonation and expression and all the rest. I can entertain people, and I do it almost continuously when I am in company, but I cannot find any way to canalize it...
May 24 - I always ask myself what Alexander Woolcott has that I haven't, but nothing much, it seems to me, ever comes out of me.
Arrangement
Organized into nine series: I. Outgoing Family Correspondence, 1918-1964. II. Incoming Family Correspondence, 1918-1964. III. General Correspondence, 1919-1964. IV. Diaries, 1925-1964. V. Manuscripts, 1916-1939. VI. "His Book," 1916-1928. VII. Printed Matter, 1920-1963. VIII. Davenport Genealogy, 1899-1932. IX. Miscellany, 1920-1962.
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century -- Archives; Translators -- United States -- 20th Century; Editors; Translators; Belknap, Julia Pritte, d. 1948; Benét, Rosemary, 1900-1962; Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971; Crowninshield, Frank, 1872-1947; Davenport, Basil, 1905-1966; Davenport, Christopher William, 1938-; Davenport, Emily Andrews Davison, 1874-1962; Davenport, Ira William, 1863-1938; Davenport, Gwen Farquharson, 1910-; Davenport, John Andrews, 1910-; Davenport, John Farquharson, 1940-; Davenport family; Davison, Ellen Scott, -1921; Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-1999; Holden, R. J. (Raymond J.), 1901-; Loveman, Amy; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940; Pratt, Fletcher, 1897-1956; Woolley, Monty, 1888-1963; Book-of-the-Month Club
- Outgoing Family Correspondence, 1918-1964; Series I; 5.2; (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  Letters from Davenport to his mother and other family members. A few are original holographs, some are original signed typescripts, but the majority are carbons retained in his own file. In cases when both the original and the copy are preserved, the pages of the copy are numbered the same as the original, with the added notation: "copy".
  - 1 - 77, 1918 - 1919 Oct 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 78-170, 1919 Oct 24 - 1920 Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 171-262, 1920 Apr 19 - 1920 Dec 13 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 263-433, 1921 Jan 9 - 1922 Jun 18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 434-582, 1922 Ju1 15 - 1923 Mar 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 583-705, 1923 Apr 8 - 1923 Dec 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 706-908, 1924 Jan 13 - 1924 Oct 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 909-1059, 1925 Jan 10 - 1925 Nov 18 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1058-1161, 1926 Jan 15 - 1926 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1162-1208, 1926 Nov 5 - 1926 Dec 25 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1209-1288, 1927 Jan 2 - 1927 Mar 31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1289-1343, 1927 Apr 1 - 1927 Jun 11 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1344-1406, 1927 Sep 19 - 1927 Dec 26 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1407-1478, 1928 Jan 12 - 1928 Jun 28 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1479-1555, 1928 Jul 7 - 1928 Dec 5 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1556-1672, 1929 Jan 4 - 1929 Dec 17 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1673-1866, 1930 Jan 15 - 1930 Dec 15 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1867-2026, 1931 Jan 14 - 1931 Dec 5 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 2027-2155, 1932 Jan 1 - 1932 Dec 14 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 2156-2329, 1933 Jan 15 - 1933 Dec 11 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 2330-2481, 1934 Jan 14 - 1934 Dec 9 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 2482-2672, 1935 Jan 6 - 1935 Dec 9 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 2673-2794, 1936 Jan 3 - 1936 Dec 15 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 2795-2878, 1937 Jan 6 - 1937 Dec 31 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 2879-2977, 1938 Jan 4 - 1938 Dec 29 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 2978-3025, 1939 Jan 5 - 1939 Jun 30 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - 3026-3085, 1939 Jul 10 - 1939 Dec 28 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - 3086-3149, 1940 Jan 5 - 1940 Jun 14 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 3150-3216, 1940 Jul 9 - 1940 Dec 17 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - 3217-3285, 1941 Jan 3 - 1941 Mar 31 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 3286-3334, 1941 Apr 1 - 1941 Jul 18 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 3335-3394, 1941 Aug 5 - 1941 Dec 18 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 3395-3485, 1942 Jan 26 - 1942 Aug 4 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 3486-3552, 1942 Aug 10 - 1942 Dec 30 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 3553-3620, 1943 Jan 4 - 1943 Mar 29 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 3621-3675, 1943 Apr 4 - 1943 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 3676-3741, 1943 Jun 2 - 1943 Aug 29 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 3742-3842, 1943 Sep 1 - 1943 Dec 25 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - 3843-3957, 1944 Jan 2 - 1944 Mar 29 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - 3958-4063, 1944 Apr 1 - 1944 May 31 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - 4064-4146, 1944 Jun 7 - 1944 Jul 31 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - 4147-4262, 1944 Aug 1 - 1944 Dec 31 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - 4263-4371, 1945 Jan 3 - 1945 Apr 23 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - 4372-4476, 1945 May 3 - 1945 Jun 28 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - 4477-4575, 1945 Jul 2 - 1945 Dec 31 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - 4576-4644, 1946 Jan 4 - 1946 Feb 28 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - 4645-4724, 1946 Mar 1 - 1946 Jun 25 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - 4725-4815, 1946 Jul 2 - 1946 Dec 31 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - 4816-4891, 1947 Jan 3 - 1947 Apr 30 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - 4892-4957, 1947 May 9 - 1947 Sep 30 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - 4958-5006, 1947 Oct 3 - 1947 Dec 31 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - 5007-5079, 1948 Jan 6 - 1948 Apr 23 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - 5080-5157, 1948 Apr 30 - 1948 Dec 30 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - 5158-5235, 1949 Jan 4 - 1949 Jun 28 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - 5236-5304, 1949 Aug 2 - 1949 Dec 19 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - 5305-5405, 1950 Jan 6 - 1950 Aug 23 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - 5406-5469, 1950 Sep 11 - 1950 Dec 13 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - 5470-5533, 1951 Jan 5 - 1951 Mar 30 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - 5534-5607, 1951 Apr 4 - 1951 May 25 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - 5608-5670, 1951 Jun 1 - 1951 Sep 26 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - 5671-5736, 1951 Oct 10 - 1951 Dec 28 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - 5737-5798, 1952 Jan 3 - 1952 Mar 27 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - 5799-5855, 1952 Apr 1 - 1952 May 27 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - 5856-5901, 1952 Jun 4 - 1952 Sep 25 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - 5902-5958, 1952 Oct 3 - 1952 Dec 31 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - 5959-6029, 1953 Jan 16 - 1953 Apr 29 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - 6030-6085, 1953 May 8 - 1953 Sep 30 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - 6086-6135, 1953 Oct 7 - 1953 Dec 31 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - 6136-6187, 1954 Jan 8 - 1954 Apr 30 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - 6188-6247, 1954 May 7 - 1954 Aug 30 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - 6248-6309, 1954 Sep 1 - 1954 Dec 27 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - 6310-6360, 1955 Jan 4 - 1955 Feb 24 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - 6361-6406, 1955 Mar 4 - 1955 Apr 28 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - 6407-6466, 1955 May 3 - 1955 Aug 26 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - 6467-6519, 1955 Sep 8 - 1955 Dec 15 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - 6520-6582, 1956 Jan 6 - 1956 Mar 20 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - 6583-6633, 1956 Apr 2 - 1956 Jun 21 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - 6634-6697, 1956 Jul 2 - 1956 Dec 13 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - 6698-6755, 1957 Jan 2 - 1957 Mar 28 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - 6756-6791, 1957 Apr 5 - 1957 Sep 26 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - 6792-6843, 1957 Oct 1 -1957 Dec 30 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - 6844-6925, 1958 Jan 2 - 1958 May 29 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - 6926-6991, 1958 Jun 6 - 1958 Dec 31 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - 6992-7048, 1959 Jan 6 - 1959 Mar 20 (Box 12, Folder 84)
  - 7049-7108, 1959 Apr 2 - 1959 Jun 22 (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - 7109-7163, 1959 Aug 9 - 1959 Dec 30 (Box 12, Folder 86)
  - 7164-7231, 1960 Jan 8 - 1960 Mar 31 (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - 7232-7315, 1960 Apr 12 -1960 Jun 30 (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - 7316-7380, 1960 Jul 1 - 1960 Sep 26 (Box 12, Folder 89)
  - 7381-7419, 1960 Oct 4 - 1960 Dec 14 (Box 12, Folder 90)
  - 7420-7478, 1961 Jan 5 - 1961 Dec 15 (Box 13, Folder 91)
  - 7479-7501, 1962 Feb 6 - 1964 Sep 29 (Box 13, Folder 92)
- Incoming Family Correspondence, 1913-1964; Series II; 0.4; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent.
  Letters from members of the Davenport family addressed to Basil Davenport. A number of them contain letters from others to the specific family member, often referring to or commenting on Basil Davenport.
  - Belknap, Juliet (Pritte) to Davenport, 1931, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - Davenport, Emily Andrews (Davison) to Juliet (Pritte) Belknap, 1935, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 94)
  - Burton, Richard to Mrs. Atwood Martin, sent to Juliet (Pritte) Belknap by Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 95)
  - Davenport, Emily Andrews (Davison) to Basil Davenport, 1920-1960 (Box 14, Folder 96)
  - Anderson, Dwight & Barbara to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 97)
  - Brock, Leland to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 98)
  - Burke, Halton W. to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 99)
  - Cole, Emily Downer to Mary Andrews with note from Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 100)
  - Davies, Charlotte A. to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 101)
  - Engerhard, Margaret to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 102)
  - Humphrey, Eleanor B. to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 103)
  - Jenkins, Elizabeth F. to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, [1917] (Box 14, Folder 104)
  - Jewett, Rutger Bleecker to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 105)
  - Markham, Anna Catherine (Murphy) to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 106)
  - Markham, Edwin to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1918, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 107)
  - Martin, Cora to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 108)
  - Nettelroth, Alexander to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 109)
  - Simmons, Grant to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 110)
  - Davenport, Christopher William to Basil Davenport, 1951-1964 (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - Davenport, Christopher William to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 112)
  - Davenport, Christopher William to Gwen (Farquharson) Davenport, 1950, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 113)
  - Davenport, Gwen (Farquharson) to Basil Davenport, 1941-1960 (Box 14, Folder 114)
  - Davenport, Gwen (Farquharson) to Christopher William Davenport, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Davenport, Gwen (Farquharson) to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1941-1956 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Davenport, Ira William to Juliet (Pritte) Belknap, 1919, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Davenport, Ira William to Basil Davenport, 1915, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Davenport, Ira William to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1913-1925 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Davenport, Ira William to John Andrews Davenport, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Davenport, Jill to Basil Davenport, [1957] (Box 14, Folder 121)
  - Davenport, Jill to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1958, undated (Box 14, Folder 122)
  - Davenport, John (Alfred) to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 123)
  - Davenport, John Andrews to Basil Davenport., 1920-1962 (Box 14, Folder 124)
  - Davenport, John Andrews to Christopher William Davenport, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Davenport, John Andrews to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1918-1955 (Box 14, Folder 126)
  - Davenport, John Andrews to Emily (Andrews) Davison, 1920, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 127)
  - Davenport, John Andrews to Ira William Davenport, 1922-1933 (Box 14, Folder 128)
  - Davenport, John Farquharson to Basil Davenport, 1955-1959 (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - Davenport, John Farquharson to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1949-1957 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Davison, Ellen Scott to Emily Andrews (Davison) Davenport, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - Davison, Ellen Scott to Ira William Davenport, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Pfohl, James Christian to Gwen (Farquharson) Davenport, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - Taft, Horace Dutton to Ira William Davenport, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Woolley, Edgar Montillon to Ira William Davenport, 1927 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Yale University to Ira William Davenport, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 136)
- General Correspondence, 1919-1964; Series III; 1.6; (4 boxes)
  Letters from and to Davenport's friends and associates. With the exception of a handful of original signed letters by him, which were subsequently returned by the recipient, his side of the correspondence consists mainly of carbon copies, which he retained in his own file. Some of the folders contain nothing but Davenport's carbons, with no incoming letters from the correspondent concerned.
  - Abramson, Ben, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 137)
  - Ackerman, Forrest J., 1954 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Adams, Carl W., [1950] (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Alden, Carella, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 140)
  - Allen, Arthur, [1958] (Box 15, Folder 141)
  - Archer, Dirce, 1956-1959 (Box 15, Folder 142)
  - Armstrong, F. H., 1939-1959 (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Artzybasheff, Elizabeth (Snyder), 1951, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - Asimov, Isaac, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Ault, Bromwell, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 146)
  - Bacon, Leonard, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 147)
  - Ballantine, Ian, 1960-1961 (Box 15, Folder 148)
  - Bates, Graham, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 149)
  - Bayley, Robert, 1946-1963 (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Beck, Calvin Thomas, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 151)
  - Benét, Laura (Baxter), 1951 (Box 15, Folder 152)
  - Benét, Rachel, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 153)
  - Benét, Rosemary (Carr), [1943]-1962 (Box 15, Folder 154)
  - Benét, Steven Vincent, 1935-1942 (Box 15, Folder 155)
  - Benét, Thomas, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 156)
  - Benét, William Rose, 1943-1949 (Box 15, Folder 157)
  - Bennett, Whitman, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 158)
  - Binsse, Henry B., 1921 (Box 15, Folder 159)
  - Bissell, Clifford Hershey, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 160)
  - Blakemore, Neville, [1943] (Box 15, Folder 161)
  - Blaustein, Albert P., 1957-1963 (Box 15, Folder 162)
  - Bliss, Robert, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 163)
  - Bond, Raymond Tostevin, 1954-1962 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - Boswell, Helen, 1954-1955 (Box 15, Folder 165)
  - Bower, Warren, [1955] (Box 15, Folder 166)
  - Boyle, James Le B., 1946 (Box 15, Folder 167)
  - Brower, Eleanore, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - Brower, Georgie, [1956] (Box 15, Folder 169)
  - Brower, Ogden, 1943-1961 (Box 15, Folder 170)
  - Brower, Treonne, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 171)
  - Brown, Joseph, 1954-1964 (Box 15, Folder 172)
  - Brownfield, Lyman, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 173)
  - Calverley, Grace, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 174)
  - Canby, Courtland, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 175)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1929, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - Caniff, Milton, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 177)
  - Carlin, Steven R., 1955 (Box 15, Folder 178)
  - Castle, Frederick, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 179)
  - Case, Harold Claude, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Caswell, A. Remington, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Catholic News, Editor of, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 182)
  - Cerf, Bennett Alfred, 1950-1963 (Box 15, Folder 183)
  - Chappell, Warren, 1958, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 184)
  - Chase, Arthur Minturn, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 185)
  - Chase, Paul T., 1954-1957 (Box 15, Folder 186)
  - Ciardi, John, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - Cochrane, Mrs. B., 1955 (Box 15, Folder 188)
  - Coghill, Neville, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 189)
  - Cogswell, Theodore R., 1958 (Box 15, Folder 190)
  - Cohn, Janet, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 191)
  - Cole, William, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - Colon, Mr., 1959 (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Couperis, Pierre, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Corn, Mrs. Charles, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 196)
  - Cowan, Mr., 1954 (Box 15, Folder 197)
  - Crane, Lucia (Walker), 1960-1963 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - Crawford, Deborah, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 199)
  - Crowinshield, Francis Welch, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 200)
  - Crowell, Robert Leland, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - Dale, George, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - Daley, Bernard, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - Dannay, Fred, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - Davenport, Marcia (Gluck), 1954, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - Davies, Charlotte A., 1945 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - Davison, Edward Lewis, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - De Camp, Lyon Sprague, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - De La Torre, Lillian, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 209)
  - De Long, Jenny (Mansbridge), 1963 (Box 15, Folder 210)
  - Dickson, Gordon R., 1960 (Box 15, Folder 211)
  - Dodd, Edward Howard, 1950-1957 (Box 15, Folder 212)
  - Dodd, Mead & Co., 1958 Sep 29 (Box 15, Folder 213)
  - Dodge, Joseph, 1939-1964 (Box 15, Folder 214)
  - Dodge, Sally, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 215)
  - Doyle, Adrian Conan, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - Du Sautoy, Peter F., 1957, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Dyer, Charlotte (Leavitt), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Dyer, George Bell, 1936, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - Eisner, Steven, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - Elliot, Mr., 1950 (Box 16, Folder 221)
  - Embry, Jacqueline, undated (Box 16, Folder 222)
  - Emerson, Sewall, 1926-1962 (Box 16, Folder 223)
  - Erskine, John, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - Eustace, John, 1954-1959 (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - Evers, John, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 226)